Guide to the Roundell Tristram Toke diaries and photographs from military service in China and Japan, 1900-1907 RL.11647
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Roundell Tristram Toke diaries and photographs from military service in China and Japan
1900-1907
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
RL.11647
1.0 Linear Feet 4 boxes Approximately 150 items
Collection comprises diaries and photographs by British officer Roundell Tristram Toke, documenting in detail his military service in China and Japan during the Boxer Rebellion and Russo-Japanese War, 1900 to 1907. The first diary is set in China; the other three in Japan. All four contain daily descriptions of weather, social and administrative activities, military engagements, rations, medical training, diplomacy, and other details, with some sketches of formations and drill patterns. The diaries are accompanied by approximately 145 photographs from China and Japan, with images of military camps, drills, equipment, engagements, destroyed areas, Russian war prisoners and their camps, towns, landscapes, harbors, a few social gatherings, and civilians. The collection also includes Toke's leather cigar case, inscribed on the inside with his postings with dates, beginning with Weihai, China, 1900.
Four diaries; leather case; approximately 145 photographs.
Biographical Note
Roundell Tristram Toke, who signed his diaries "R.T. Toke," was born in Crewkerne, Somerset, November 9, 1869. He was a British officer, first serving in 1888 in the 4th Battalion, Devonshire Regiment, then in the Welsh Regiment, Chinese Regiment, 1892, rising in rank to Lieutenant Colonel by 1916. In addition to his military service in China and Japan, he served in World War I from 1914-1918, commanding the 6th Battalion, Bedfordshire Regiment, from August 24, 1915-May 3, 1916. Toke died November 23, 1957, in Kent.
Historical Note
After the Russian Empire leased Port Arthur from China for 25 years in March 1898, the United Kingdom pressured the Chinese government into leasing Wei-hai-wei as anchorage for the Royal Navy's China Station and a port of call for ships of the Royal Navy in the Far East. To protect the British interests, a British army regiment was formed consisting of Chinese rank and file under British officers. Among those officers was Captain Toke of the Welsh Regiment, the author of the diaries and the photographer who created the images in this collection.
Conditions Governing Access
Collection is open for research. A small group of rolled photographs are slated for conservation treatment and are temporarily closed to access.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Roundell Tristram Toke diaries and photographs were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a purchase in 2018.
Related Materials
Related collection: Friedrich Carl Peetz photographs, 1900, Rubenstein Library, Duke University.
Related collection: William Hillman Shockley photographs, 1896-1922 and undated, bulk 1897-1909, Rubenstein Library, Duke University.
Related collection: M. F. Wilson diary, 1903 September 21-1904 September 20, Rubenstein Library, Duke University.
Content Description
Collection comprises autograph manuscript diaries and photographs of British officer Roundell Tristram Toke, during his service in China and Japan during the Boxer Rebellion and Russo-Japanese War, 1900 to 1907. The diaries contain daily descriptions of weather, social and administrative activities, regiment training and drills, military engagements, rations, Japanese prisoner of war camps for the Russians, medical training, foreign diplomacy, and other details. Some contain sketches of formations and drill patterns. The first diary, from 1900, describes service in China during the Boxer Rebellion, while the last three, January 1905-November 1907, detail his service in Japan as an attache` at the British Embassy in Tokyo and military consultant to the Japanese during and after the Russo-Japanese War.
Toke's diaries are accompanied by approximately 145 photographs: 40 unmounted larger albumen and 105 smaller silver gelatin prints. These images vividly document his time in China and Japan, showing military camps, officers, drills, engagements, landmark battle and burial sites such as 203 Metre Hill, Russian prisoners and their camp, towns, harbors, destroyed railroads and buildings, and Chinese and Japanese civilians. There are a few more personal photos of Western women, children, and men. A series of larger images from China depict the destruction and death caused by the conflict of 1900.
The collection includes Toke's leather cigar case, inscribed on the inside with his postings with dates, beginning with Wei-Hai-Wei in China, 1900.
Photography -- China; Photography -- Japan; Prisoners of war -- Russian -- Japan -- 1900-1910 -- Photographs; Russo-Japanese War, 1904-1905 -- Military personnel -- British; Russo-Japanese War, 1904-1905 -- Personal narratives, British; Russo-Japanese War, 1904-1905 -- Photographs; Soldiers -- Great Britain -- Diaries; China -- History -- Boxer Rebellion, 1899-1901 -- Military personnel -- British; China -- History -- Boxer Rebellion, 1899-1901 -- Personal narratives, British; China -- Photographs; China -- Social life and customs -- 1644-1912; Great Britain -- Foreign relations -- Japan; Japan -- Foreign relations -- Great Britain; Japan -- Photographs; Japan -- Social life and customs -- 1868-1912; Weihai (China) -- Photographs; Albumen prints; Diaries; Gelatin silver prints; Black-and-white photographs; Great Britain. Army. Welch Regiment.; Great Britain. Army -- Colonial forces -- China -- History; Toke, Roundell Tristram, 1869-1957
- Diaries, 1900, 1905-1907
  Scope and Contents
  Roundell Tristram Toke's personal narratives of his military service in China and Japan take the form of three bound commercial daily diaries and one disbound diary, housed in two custom boxes. A leather cigar case is with the diaries.
  The first volume dates from January through December 1900, and recounts Toke's service in China during the Boxer Rebellion.
  After his service in China, Captain Toke was transferred to Japan, serving as a military attaché at the British Embassy in Tokyo, evidently tasked with serving as a military advisor to the Japanese with a particular emphasis on artillery matters. The signing of the Anglo-Japanese Alliance in 1902 and the outbreak of the Russo-Japanese War in 1904 led to increased cooperation between the Japanese and British military.
  The other three daily diaries relate to this period, describing his military and diplomatic activities in Japan in 1905, 1906, and 1907.
  Included with Toke's diaries are approximately 145 loose photographs (including some duplicates) taken by him in this period, including military camps, landscapes, civilians, war scenes, and Russian prisoners of war in their camps. Many are captioned in his hand. The photographs are described in a separate series in this collection guide.
  - China, 1900 January-December; 1 Volumes In custom box with two other volumes. (Box 1)
    Includes two mounted photographs.
    One bound commercial diary filled with almost daily entries by Toke, detailing his service in China during the Boxer Rebellion. The life of an officer at the camp Wei-hai-wei included much dining, sightseeing, and playing sports, until Chinese anti-colonial militias began their violent uprising. In March 1900, Toke writes of dispersing unlawful assemblies in neighboring villages, followed by battles to put down the rebellion, and scenes of destruction, with dead and wounded soldiers as well as many civilians. Included with this diary are approximately 40 photographs of China, many depicting the destruction relating to the rebellion. Many of the images are captioned in pencil on verso, evidently at a later date.
  - Japan, 1905 January-1906 December; 2 Volumes In custom box with one other volume. (Box 1)
    Two bound commercial diaries, filled with almost daily entries recounting Toke's service as an attaché to the British Embassy in Tokyo. Besides numerous entries concerning the weather, his travel within Japan, his dining companions (including notable government officials and nobility), and living arrangements, he also includes some insights into military matters (including details relating to the Battle of Mukden), although does not appear to have seen any action himself.
    Included in the rear of the diaries are listings of various financial accounts. Attached in some capacity to the Japanese Army during the Russo-Japanese War, he was decorated by the Japanese for his assistance and was involved in transporting captured Russian guns.
  - Japan and China, 1907 June 10-November 4; 1 Volumes Housed in custom-made box. (Box 2)
    Disbound but with the original upper wrapper present, this 212-page diary covers a brief period following the Russo-Japanese War in which Toke was attached to the 1st Regiment of Imperial Guard at Takehashi Barracks. His detailed observations concern the military maneuvers and exercises of the regiment, as well as their outfitting, arms, daily rations, and organization. He also comments on social gatherings and individuals he meets.
    Illustrated with many sketches of military formations and maneuvers, and with two mounted photographs showing troops on a firing range. A few official handwritten letters sent to Toke (including several from a Captain Saito), are mounted on the pages.
    Original paper cover bears label with Toke's name and location, and handwritten title: "Diary during attachment to 1st Regiment of Guards, Tokio."
- Photographs, 1900-1907; 145 photographs 2 boxes
  Conditions Governing Access
  Approximately 40 rolled photographs are closed until conservation treatment is completed.
  Series contains over 140 photographs taken by Roundell Tristram Toke while he was in military service in China (1900) and Japan (1905-1907). A small group of approximately 40 photographs taken in China are larger in size and may be unmounted albumen prints.
  The 103 loose photographs in this group are all early gelatin silver prints measuring 3x4 inches with some minor variations. The earliest are contact prints. Judging from the two envelopes marked with Captain Toke's name, the developing was done by the Kusakabe Kimbei studio in Tokyo or Yokohama. The first prints in this group are four hand-colored photographs of three geishas and a garden; although the size and similarity of these to the other photographs indicate they may have been taken by Toke, the hand-tinting may be the work of the Kimbei studio. Also present in the first few photographs is a small full-length standing portrait of Lieutenant Colonel Toke in dress uniform.
  A small group of approximately 40 photographs taken in China are larger in size and may be unmounted albumen prints. They are tightly rolled and in the Conservation lab; closed pending completion of treatment.
  - No known title, circa 1905-1907; 3x4 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0001)
    Title (Chinese)
    未标题
    Title (Japanese)
    無題
    Descriptive note
    Three geishas, kneeling in garden in \see no evil, hear no evil, speak no evil\ postures.
    Descriptive note (Chinese)
    三位艺伎跪坐着，分别做着"不听"，"不看"，"不说" 坏事的姿势
  - No known title, circa 1905-1907; 3x4 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0002)
    Three geishas, standing.
    三位艺伎站着
  - No known title, circa 1905-1907; 3x4 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0003)
    Three geishas, in garden, playing blind man's bluff.
    三位艺伎在花园中玩捉迷藏
  - Iris garden, circa 1905-1907; 4x3 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0004)
    堀切菖蒲園
    堀切菖蒲園（東京都葛飾区堀切二丁目にある葛飾区所管の公園（植物園））
  - Self, circa 1905-1907; 4 1/8 x 3 1/4 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0005)
    摄影师本人照片
    撮影師本人写真
    Standing portrait of R.T. Toke.
    托克站立照
  - River Liao, circa 1905; 3x4 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0006)
    辽河
    遼河
    Description
    Legacy id: A7
  - 3rd Army / Fa-Ku Men, circa 1905; 3x4 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0007)
    法库门（法库县）
    法庫門（法庫県）
    Legacy id: C10. Fakumen was an area in China with an important railway station.
  - No known title, circa 1905-1907; 3x4 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0008)
    Group of Chinese workers, one carrying two tall sheaves.
    几个中国民工，一人挑着柴草担子
    Legacy id: C12
  - Field artillery / 3rd Army, circa 1905; 3x4 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0009)
    大炮 / 第三军队
    大砲／第３部隊
    Legacy id: D2
  - No known title, circa 1905; 3x4 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0010)
    Soldiers and artillery guns in action on field.
    炮兵们在操练
    Legacy id: D3
  - No known title, circa 1905-1907; 3x4 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0011)
    Horse-drawn wagon with captured gun.
    马车拉着缴获的枪炮
    Legacy id: D5
  - Captured Russian gun, circa 1905-1907; 3x4 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0012)
    缴获的俄国炮
    押収されたロシアの砲
    Legacy id: D7
  - Top of 203 Metre Hill, 1905 September; 3x4 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0013.1)
    203 高地山顶
    二百三高地山頂
    Yantai (Shandong, China)
  - 203 Metre Hill, 1905 September; 3x4 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0013.2)
    203 高地
    二百三高地
  - 203 M. Hill, 1905 September; 3x4 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0014)
  - The summit of 203 M. Hill, 1905 September; 4x3 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0015.1)
  - The top of 203 M. Hill, 1905 September; 4x3 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0015.2)
  - Tera-yama [illegible] Yentai, circa 1905; 3x4 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0016)
    烟台芝罘毓璜顶外国人墓地
    烟台（市）芝罘（区）毓璜顶（今は公園？）外国人墓地
  - View looking over Port Arthur from 203 M. Hill, 1905 September; 3x4 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0017.1)
    从203高地山顶远眺旅顺港
    二百三高地山頂から旅順港を遠く覗む（遠景）
  - View from 203 M. Hill, 1905 September; 3x4 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0017.2)
    从203高地山顶远眺
    二百三高地山頂から覗む
  - View from top of 203 M. Hill, 1905 September; 3x4 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0018.1)
  - View of Port Arthur from 203 M. Hill, 1905 September; 3x4 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0018.2)
  - Japanese and Russian graves on 203 M. Hill, 1905; 4x3 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0019.1)
    203高地山顶的日本人和俄国人墓地
    二百三高地山頂の日本人とロシア人墓地
  - Russian graves on 203 M. Hill, 1905; 4x3 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0019.2)
    203高地山顶的俄国人墓地
    二百三高地山頂のロシア人墓地
  - Graves on top of 203 M. Hill, 1905; 4x3 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0020.1)
    203高地山顶的墓地
    二百三高地山頂の墓地
  - Japanese graves on top of 203 M. Hill, 1905; 4x3 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0020.2)
    203高地山顶的日本人墓地
    二百三高地山頂の日本人墓地
  - Shipping captured Russian guns at Dalny, 1905; 3x4 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0021.1)
    在大连将缴获的俄国枪炮装船
    大連で押収したロシアの銃の出荷
    Dalny was the Russian name for a port town in northeastern China on the Liaodong Peninsula; in Japanese it became known as Dalian or Ta-lien, and Darien. Now known as Dalian (Liaoning Sheng, China).
  - Loading / Embarking captured Russian guns at Dalny, 1905; 3x4 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0021.2)
  - Shipping captured Russian guns at Dalny, 1905; 4x3 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0022.1)
  - Shipping captured guns at Dalny, 1905; 4x3 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0022.2)
    在大连将缴获的枪炮装船
    大連で押収された銃の出荷
    Dalian (Liaoning Sheng, China)
  - No known title, 1905; 3x4 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0023.1)
    Shipping captured guns.
    在大连装运缴获的枪炮
  - No known title, 1905; 3x4 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0023.2)
  - Dalny, 1905 September; 3x4 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0024.1)
    大连
    大連
    Bridge over railway.
    火车道上的桥梁
  - Dalny bridge over railway, 1905 September; 3x4 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0024.2)
    大连，火车道上的桥梁
    大連／電車道上の橋
  - Gate on the Great [Willow] Pallisade, circa 1905; 4x3 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0025.1)
    柳条边边门
    柳条辺辺門
  - Willow Pallisade, circa 1905; 4x3 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0025.2)
    柳条边
    柳条辺
  - Gate in old Willow Pallisade, circa 1905; 4x3 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0026.1)
  - The Great Willow Pallisade, circa 1905; 4x3 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0026.2)
  - Transport carts / H.Q. 2nd Army, 1905; 4x3 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0027.1)
    运输车队 / 第二军
    輸送車隊/第二軍
  - Japanese transport carts, 1905; 4x3 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0027.2)
    日本运输车队
    日本輸送車隊
  - A break on the railway / bridge washed away, 1905 September; 3x4 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0028.1)
    铁路被毁处 / 桥被冲走
    鉄道破壊／橋が壊れて流されること
  - A break in the line / bridge washed away on my return home, 1905 September; 3x4 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0028.2)
    回家的路上铁路被毁处 / 桥被冲走
    帰路の途中鉄道破壊／橋が流される
  - Break in railway during war / coolies carrying baggage from one train to the other, 1905 September; 3x4 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0029.1)
    战争中被毁的铁路 / 苦力们挑着行李从一辆列车到另一辆
    戦争中に破壊された鉄道／クーリーが電車から電車に荷物を運んでいる
  - Our baggage being carried from one train to another / the bridge was washed away, 1905 September; 3x4 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0029.2)
    苦力们把我们的行李从一辆车挑到另一辆 / 桥被冲走
    そのクーリーたちは私たちの荷物をある車両から別の車両に乗せた。／橋が流される
  - Russian rolling stock burnt by Russians, circa 1905; 3x4 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0030.1)
    俄国人将他们的火车焚毁
    ロシア人はデンさｈを燃やした
  - Destroyed Russian rolling stock, circa 1905; 3x4 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0030.2)
    被焚毁的俄国火车
    燃えたロシアの電車
  - Station on Manchurian Railway 80 m. from Dalny, circa 1905; 3x4 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0031.1)
    满洲铁路上的一站，距离大连80英里
    満州鉄道で1駅、大連から80マイル
  - Manchurian Railway, circa 1905; 3x4 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0031.2)
    满洲铁路
    満州鉄道
  - Artillery practice H-Q 2nd Army, circa 1905; 4x3 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0032.1)
    炮兵们在操练 / 第二军
    砲兵の操練／第二軍
  - Artillery in action, circa 1905; 4x3 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0032.2)
    炮兵们在行动
    砲兵たちの行動
  - Musketry practice H-Q. 2nd Army, 1905 September; 4x3 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0033.1)
    步兵们在操练 / 第二军
  - Musketry practice H-Q. 2nd Army, 1905 September; 4x3 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0033.2)
  - Artillery practice H-Q 2nd Army, circa 1905; 3x4 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0034.1)
  - Artillery coming into action, circa 1905; 3x4 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0034.2)
    炮兵们准备行动
    砲兵の準備駆動行動
  - Carts fording river, circa 1905; 3x4 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0035.1)
    大车拉着辎重过河
    大車を引っ張って河を渡る
  - Transport crossing a river, circa 1905; 3x4 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0035.2)
    行军过河
    行軍渡河
  - Stuck in the mud / H.Q. 2nd Army, circa 1905; 3x4 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0036)
    大车陷入泥中 / 第二军
    大車は泥中に陥没／第二軍
  - Bridge making / H.Q. 2nd Army, circa 1905; 3x4 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0037)
    搭桥 / 第二军
    橋渡／第二軍
  - Manchu women making bean paste, circa 1905; 4x3 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0038)
    满族妇女磨豆子
    豆を挽く満州族の婦人
  - Making bean paste / Manchurian village, circa 1905; 3x4 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0039)
    磨豆子 / 满族村子
    粉砕豆／満州族の村人
  - Transport crossing a river, circa 1905; 3x4 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0040.1)
    军队运送物资过河
    軍隊輸送物資橋渡
  - Crossing a river / H.Q. 2nd Army, circa 1905; 3x4 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0040.2)
    过河 / 第二军
    渡河／第二軍
  - Transport carts, circa 1905; 4x3 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0041)
    运输队
    運輸隊（輸送隊）
  - Carts bringing in supplies to H.Q. 2nd Army, circa 1905; 4x3 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0042.1)
    给第二军运来物资的车队
    第二軍に物資を輸送した軍隊
  - A muddy load [?] / H.Q. 2nd Army, circa 1905; 4x3 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0042.2)
    给第二军运来物资的车队走在泥泞的路上
    第二軍に物資を輸送した軍隊は泥に嵌っています。
  - Target practice / H.Q. 2nd Army, circa 1905; 4x3 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0043)
    射击训练 / 第二军
    射撃訓練／第二軍
  - Mukden, circa 1905; 4x3 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0044.1)
    奉天（沈阳）
    奉天（瀋陽）
  - Mukden during the war, circa 1905; 4x3 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0044.2)
    战争中的奉天（沈阳）
    戦争中の奉天（瀋陽）
  - Mukden, circa 1905; 4x3 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0045.1)
  - Mukden, circa 1905; 4x3 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0045.2)
  - Imperial Palace Mukden, 1905 September; 3x4 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0046)
    奉天（沈阳）皇宫
    奉天（瀋陽）皇宮
  - No known title, circa 1905; 3x4 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0047)
    Man in the middle of a large group of children gathered in a circle outside a building.
    屋子外的一群孩童，中间有一个大人
  - Station on Manchurian Railway / river in flood / 80 miles from Dalny, circa 1905; 3x4 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0048)
    满洲铁路车站 / 河流中的洪水 / 距离大连80英里
    満州鉄道駅／河で洪水／距離大連８０マイル
  - Tieh-Ling / reinforcements going to the front, 1905 September; 4x3 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0049)
    铁岭 / 运上前线的军需物资
    鉄嶺／最前線の軍需物資
  - Imperial duck hunt Tokyo lunch / each guest had a charcoal chafing dish in front of him in which the duck was cooked, circa 1905; 4x3 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0050)
    猎鸭后的宫廷式午宴 / 每位客人面前都有一个炭火炉来煮食鸭肉
    鴨狩後の宮廷式の昼食会／各客人の前には料理用の木炭ストーブがあります
  - Reinforcements from Japan / cavalry regiment / Tieh-Ling, 1905; 3x4 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0051)
    从日本新增的骑兵团 / 铁岭
    日本からの新騎兵連隊／鉄嶺（遼寧省鉄嶺市？）
  - Tieh-Ling, 1905; 3x4 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0052.1)
    铁岭
    鉄嶺
    View of camp with horse pickets.
    军营中站在栏杆处的马匹
  - Tieh-Ling, 1905; 3x4 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0052.2)
  - Tieh-Ling / reinforcements arriving from Japan, 1905; 4x3 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0053.1)
    铁岭 / 从日本新增的骑兵团
    鉄嶺／日本からの新騎兵連隊
  - Tieh-Ling / reinforcements going to the front, 1905; 4x3 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0053.2)
  - Making a bridge across river / H.Q. 2nd Army, 1905; 3x4 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0054)
    筑桥过河 / 第二军
    築橋渡河／第二軍
    This print is numbered 1 in a sequence of two prints.
  - Bridge completed, 1905; 3x4 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0055)
    筑好的桥
    新しい橋の建築
    This print is numbered 2 in a sequence of two prints.
  - Gun for firing bombs / Gen. Oseko / Cap. Kurihara / Takayahagi [?], circa 1905; 3x4 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0056)
    小炮 / Oseko将军 / Kurihara上校 / Takayahagi [?] 上校
    小砲／大迫将軍／栗原大佐、高柳大佐（？）
    Oseko commanded the 7th Division.
  - Japanese portable forge at work, circa 1905; 3x4 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0057)
    日式便携式锻造工具
    日本式手工鍛造工具
  - Shoeing horses / H.Q. 2nd Army / 13 m. W. of Kai-Yüan, circa 1905; 4x3 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0058)
    钉马掌 / 第二军 / 开原以西13英里处
    釘馬掌／第二軍／開原（市）以西１３マイル（２１ｋｍ）
  - A.D.C. [to?] Emperor inspecting bomb gun, circa 1905; 3x4 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0059)
    侍从武官检查小火炮
    侍従武官の小火砲検査
  - Gun for firing bombs, circa 1905; 4x3 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0060)
    小火炮
    小火砲
  - 203 m., circa 1905; 3x4 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0061)
    View of 203 Meter Hill.
  - 203 m., circa 1905; 3x4 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0062)
  - 203 m., circa 1905; 3x4 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0063)
  - No known title, circa 1905-1907; 3x4 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0064)
    View of a harbor and hills from back of a moving ship or boat.
    从船上眺望海湾和群山
  - Beppu S. Japan, circa 1905-1907; 3x4 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0065)
    別府市，日本
    別府市、日本
  - No known title, circa 1905-1907; 3x4 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0066)
    Five-member family group posed in garden.
    六人家庭合影
  - Davidson, Somerville, and Nakamura drinking sake, circa 1905-1907; 3x4 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0067)
    坐着一起喝清酒的戴维森, 萨默维尔, 和Nakamura
    デヴィッドソンさん、ソマーヴィル・中村さん清酒を飲む
    Probably Colin J. Davidson (1878-1930), a Japan specialist in the British Consular Service, with John A.C. Somerville, British military attaché.
  - Beppu, circa 1905-1907; 3x4 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0068)
    別府市